So we are going to facilitate a trauma scenario now.
So you can see we have a mannequin on the floor with blankets.
The blankets are supposed to be snow.
It's not really snow, but we're hoping it's just enough to get our participants in that mindset to go with it.
Okay, so these are the vital signs.
And really the point of this scenario is for our responders to respond to the scene, perform an assessment.
And what they're going to find is that the patient has a pneumo.
I'll show you that again.
Clicking on the lungs, and then clicking on pneumothorax, I can then choose which side.
So I'm going to give them a right-sided pneumo, and then activate.
There might be some other injuries that are hard to simulate using the mannequin.
So as the facilitator, I will be verbalizing what those are if the participants actually assess them or look for those things.
OK.
Chart 53.
27-year-old male, ATV rollover, no helmet, County Road 1643.
Time now, 1430.
Roger that, we're on it.
Hello!
Alright, DSI, scene safe.
Looks like we have a 27-year-old male.
Unresponsive.
Sir, can you hear me?
My name is Hans with the ambulance service.
My partner, Ted.
Can you hear me, sir?
Can you hear me?
Unresponsive.
Let's get to the vitals here.
I'm going to start checking for any injuries.
My pen light, shiny eyes.
Pupils react to light?
Pupils are reactive to light.
Checking for any decapital loss in the head, eye injuries, mouth, nose.
Negative.
JVD, tracheal deviation.
Any clavicle injuries?
Negative.
I'm going to also take the lung sounds here.
Okay, no lung sounds on the right.
That's correct.
I'm going to confirm that.
I only have the chest wires on the left.
That's correct, yep.
Okay, so we have a possible tension pneumo.
I'm going to stop right there and we're going to actually, I'm going to grab you the needle out of the bag there.
We're going to needle the chest here.
I'm going to do a second intercostal space, mid-tellicular, just above the rib.
I'm actually going to need a little chest because that's expensive.
Okay, need a little chest.
Do I hear any type of... You do.
Okay, so I'm going to reconfer and I do have chest rise on the right side now.
You do.
Abdominal area.
Abdomen's soft.
Okay.
Pelvis.
Some instability.
Okay, so notice I'm going to stop there.
I'm going to put a pelvic binder on my partner and my arm.
Okay, see you partner.
The woman first when we were levitating.
A little higher.
Perfect, okay.
Okay, hold down.
Okay, pelvic stabilized.
Now down on the left leg here.
Checking for any injuries.
Negative.
Pulses?
Pulses are intact.
Okay.
Circuitry with your toes?
No response.
Okay, down on the other leg here.
Negative.
Okay.
Start blood pressure.
Don't prep pulse.
Pulse is intact.
Okay.
Left arm, same pulse.
Pulse is intact.
No response.
Right arm pulses.
Pulse is intact.
Blood pressure is 90 over 40.
Heart rate is 125.
Alright, the syringes we have are the right pneumo which has been something.
It's been fixed.
We'll keep an eye on the right side in case it reinflates.
Pelvis is stabilized.
Let's go ahead and get him on a longboard and we'll get out of here.